<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Breaking news | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/breaking-news/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-26T10:01:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Our Prediction for the Event Later Today]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/our-prediction-for-the-event-later-today/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/our-prediction-for-the-event-later-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>MechaSteve.</p>

<p>Jony Ive has spent the past few months perfecting an entirely Liquidmetal body for our beloved CEO and visionary. From his new skin he can rule benevolently over all for many years to come. </p>

<p> </p>

<p>Oh and new iPads.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Delayposting about the event of awesomeness.]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/delayposting-about-the-event-of-awesomeness/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/delayposting-about-the-event-of-awesomeness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>**10:00- **Steve is on stage! But not made of metal, which is disappointing.</p>

<p><strong>10:05-</strong> iPads are selling like really expensive hotcakes. Everyone loves them.</p>

<p>**10:15- **Doctors can show you your x-rays without you getting out of bed with their iPad. “This is where we think I left my watch,” says Dr. Johnson.</p>

<p>**10:16- **Kids love iPads too! Who knew?</p>

<p>**10:17- **The iPad…loves you. It loves children. It’s basically an angel of love and light and love.</p>

<p><strong>10:18-</strong> iPad 2 gets announced today. Say goodbye to the copycats.</p>

<p>**10:19- **New Processor! Faster! Dual core! Did we mention faster? It’s faster. That’s why it’s called “A5”.</p>

<p><strong>10:20-</strong> Cameras! Gyroscopes! Miracles!</p>

<p>**10:21- **It’s thinner too. Faster! Thinner! Cameras!</p>

<p>**10:22- **White iPad. ugly.</p>

<p>**10:23- **Verision and AT&amp;T. I have nothing to say about that.</p>

<p>**10:24- **The white one is still really ugly.</p>

<p>**10:25- **The prices, they no move. No come down, but no go up. So there you go.</p>

<p>**10:25- **They ship on March 11th. Take that, all you other tablets that haven’t shipped yet.</p>

<p>**10:27- **For $40 you can have a weird port splitter thing. Charge and use all at once! You know you want it.</p>

<p>**10:30- **Weird new magno-roll-up cover thingy. Looks…cool? if you like the color light blue.</p>

<p>**10:31- **A RAINBOW of colors! A rainbow that includes three shades of what amounts to “black or gray” And executive leather covers. For the discerning user.</p>

<p><strong>10:32-</strong> Scott Forestall is out, and is feeling intense about iOS 4.3</p>

<p>**10:35- **iPad switch does what YOU want, baby. It’s your switch. As long as you want it to mute or lock rotation.</p>

<p>**10:36- **iPhone 4 is now a hotspot.</p>

<p>**10:37- **Photobooth demos. I’m still not over the original OSX photobooth demos. Please stop.</p>

<p><strong>10:39-</strong> FaceTime. Yep. Yep.</p>

<p>**10:41- **Big stuff coming out on March 11th.</p>

<p>**10:42- **iMovie for iPad. All the Pixar engineers who have been working with iMovie for iPhone breathe a sigh of relief. Finally! a slightly larger screen!</p>

<p><strong>10:44-</strong> iMovie for iPad is…a lot like the OSX version. But it’s got a cool marquee thing on the home screen, so that’s cool, right?</p>

<p><strong>10:48-</strong> My limited patience for iMovie demos is coming to an end. Seriously, guys. Move on.</p>

<p>**10:49- **Steve just revealed how old he is “It blows my mind, this stuff.” He may have well added “What with the tapping and the rotating and the looking and the making movies? I don’t know.”</p>

<p>**10:50- **GarageBand for iPad. This one make sense. But still, the demo better be short.</p>

<p>**10:52- **Moving on. Okay, thanks for the GarageBand demo. Moving on now. Please?</p>

<p><strong>10:53-</strong> “This is a window into a much larger piano”. I’m pretty sure that’s not how that works.</p>

<p>**10:55- **Apparently the rest of the demo is all GarageBand, all the time.</p>

<p>**10:56- **Drums. DO NOT USE DRUMSTICKS! Use your fingers. Or our new iSticks.</p>

<p><strong>10:57-</strong> Smart guitar: the guitar is smart, so you don’t have to be.</p>

<p>**11:00- **Okay, I’m going to just be over there somewhere until they’re done talking about GarageBand. Talk amongst yourselves.</p>

<p>**11:03- **Garage band is finally done. That was painful.</p>

<p>**11:05- **“Now we made a video that I’d love to show you.” Did they make it in iMovie on an iPad 2?</p>

<p>**11:06- **Jony Ive likes the iPad 2 A. LOT.</p>

<p><strong>11:09-</strong> Kinda bummed they didn’t make iWeb for the iPad.</p>

<p>**11:11- **Steve is on stage, wrapping things up…hopefully. Unless he’s got some cool news about something else.</p>

<p>**11:12- **Steve is giving a speech about DNA and technology and stuff. It sounds kinda mystical.</p>

<p>**11:13- **And that’s all folks! Thanks for joining us in joining others…or something. And remember, if you enjoyed this post, why not buy your editor an iPad 2? It’s the classy thing to do.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New iPads Coming, Old iPads Attempting To Stay Calm]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/new-ipads-coming-old-ipads-attempting-to-stay-calm/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/new-ipads-coming-old-ipads-attempting-to-stay-calm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>This just in:</p>

<p>[![the graphic from the iPad event invite][2]][2]
No, I wasn’t invited. Why would I be invited? I’m a nobody, man. </p>

<p>Expect people all over the world to start ditching their iPads in preparation for new iPads, and expect Android tablets to start wondering why they’re not competitive anymore[1][2] .<br />
Expect Tim Cook to try to be somewhere near as cool as The Steve. Expect a large number of superlatives from Jony Ive about the new device. Expect me to start subtly begging for money so I can buy one of the blasted things. <br />
And, as always, expect a not-exactly-live post from me covering the event in hard-to-follow detail.</p>

<p>[]: http://crazyapplenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/iPad-Invite-Graphic.jpg
 [2]: #footnote<em>0</em>1091 “not that they have ever really been competitive…”</p>

<p>We’ll be interviewing a current Gen iPad as soon as we find someone who is willing to let us talk to their iPad and not think it’s weird.</p>

<ol>
  <li>not that they have ever really been competitive… [<a href="#identifier_0_1091">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Mac App Store: Questions]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/01/mac-app-store-questions/"/>
    <updated>2011-01-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/01/mac-app-store-questions</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>We’re not really ready to post a full on iFAQ about the Mac App Store, because we haven’t upgraded to 10.6.6 yet. So we’re going to ask pointed questions in an effort to stir up pointless controversy. Mostly because it sounds like fun.</p>

<ul>
  <li>Is it true that the App Store will be giving a percentage of every purchase to the DEVIL?</li>
  <li>What if I want to offer a free trial version of my app? 
    <ul>
      <li>What do you mean that iOS developers already do that just fine?</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Does the app store represent the end of the free market?</li>
  <li>Will all my base belong to Apple? 
    <ul>
      <li>Is it too early to hop on the retro “All your base” wagon?</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>What happens if Apple discovers they secretly hate an App after they said they liked it? Will it disappear off my mac?</li>
  <li>Is there anything in the app store, either by intent or by accident, that will make it easier for John Mayer to invade my computer? 
    <ul>
      <li>Norah Jones is fine.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
  <li>Fun bonus question: Come up with the best name for Microsoft’s copycat App store that will probably be announced either at CES or later this year! 
    <ul>
      <li>Our guess: Windows Live Program Marketplace 8.</li>
    </ul>
  </li>
</ul>

<p>That’s all we have for today. Expect a really nice iFAQ tomorrow after we’ve had some time to play with the dang thing. Well, actually don’t. Whenever we promise a post bad things happen to it before we actually get it posted. So seek to manage your expectations accordingly. We’ll keep you posted.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple&#8217;s Big Announcement Tomorrow]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/11/apples-big-announcement-tomorrow/"/>
    <updated>2010-11-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/11/apples-big-announcement-tomorrow</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>So, Apple has spammed the iTunes store with “We’re about to do something amazing” type banners, and nobody knows what’s actually coming. Not <a href="http://daringfireball.net/linked/2010/11/15/itunes-teaser">John Gruber</a>, not <a href="http://ihnatko.com/2010/11/15/an-exciting-announcement-from-itunes-tomorrow/">Andy Ihnatko</a>, not even me. I can’t tell you how happy this makes me. In these days when all corporate secrets are leaked/rumored/left in bars it’s nice to have something come up that actually catches people flatfooted. All the respected technology pundits are stumped, and it’s refreshing and kinda fun.<a href="#footnote_0_1000" title="Also kinda fun: WordPress informs me that this is officially the 1000th post on this site. Happy 1K Day, everyone!">1</a></p>

<p>However, unlike the aforementioned respected technology pundits, I have no reputation for veracity and can therefore speculate like crazy. And since I’m slightly ahead of the curve on my <a href="http://www.nanowrimo.org/eng/user/429107">NaNoWriMo </a>story, I figured I can spend some time making things up in this world instead of my novel world. These, then, are my terrible guesses about tomorrow’s announcement.</p>

<ul>
  <li><strong>Angry Birds for Mac</strong>. People will be quick to point out that the Mac is already capable of playing Angry Birds and listening to Pandora at the same time, which gives it a significant advantage over the iPad. Right-minded people will continue to wonder why these two apps continue to be the yardstick against which all new OS/hardware combos are measured.</li>
  <li>**iOS 5.0 **“We’re just gonna launch it, and the developers can catch up when they do.” An insanely-pleased-with-himself Steve Jobs will announce.</li>
  <li><strong>Apple buys Oracle</strong>. “THIS is why we’re not making our own Java any more. We just BOUGHT Java! And Solaris. And MySQL. Oh yeah, and that Oracle and PeopleSoft garbage. We’ll EOL those shortly. But hey, what do you all think about ‘iDatabase’ as the new name for MySQL?”<a href="#footnote_1_1000" title="What boundless hatred for Oracle? I don’t have a boundless hatred for Oracle! I keep my hatred for Oracle down to three hours a week max.">2</a></li>
  <li><strong>New iPod Nanos that are actually good again</strong>. “We’re renaming the old ones “ShuffleTouches”, which sounds kinda racy but actually isn’t,” Phil Schiller will explain.</li>
  <li><strong>Free Upgrade to Lion for everyone!</strong><a href="#footnote_2_1000" title="Only in the iTunes Store">3</a> . Apple will get people warmed up for the Mac App Store by making Lion a free upgrade in the current iTunes store. Critics will have a hard time deciding if this is an example of incredible generosity or a cynical way to line up all Apple users like sheep for the shearing as they start to buy all their software via Apple.</li>
  <li><strong>Peter Oppenheimer Will Finally Finish Portal</strong>: Apple’s CFO will finish the iconic first-person-puzzle-shooter on stage and broadcast live via iTunes. “This is a triumph!” Steve Jobs will say. Jonathan Coulton and Natalie Imbruglia<a href="#footnote_3_1000" title="I know she had nothing to do with Portal, but she’s got a nice voice and doesn’t get nearly enough air time these days.">4</a> will then come out on stage and sing an acoustic version of the closing credits song. Everyone who watches the broadcast will have “<a href="http://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Y6ljFaKRTrI">Still Alive</a>” stuck in their heads for weeks. <em>Again</em>.</li>
  <li><strong>Apple buys Oracle *and *Sweden</strong>. These two acquisitions will be mentioned in passing. The rest of the announcement will be 45 minutes of Steve Jobs and Jony Ive showing off their cool houses they made in <a href="http://minecraft.net/">Minecraft</a>. Notch<a href="#footnote_4_1000" title="The developer of Minecraft">5</a> will be named “A National Treasure” and will eventually have to get a restraining order against Jerry Bruckheimer and Nicholas Cage so they will stop trying to steal him from his office.</li>
</ul>

<p>Well, we could go on, but we’re mild and modest<a href="#footnote_5_1000" title="This is a lie. All bloggers have huge egos.">6</a> and don’t want to look *too *prescient in public. Feel free to put on your tinfoil hat and guess what Apple is up to in the comments.</p>

<ol>
  <li>Also kinda fun: WordPress informs me that this is officially the 1000th post on this site. Happy 1K Day, everyone! [<a href="#identifier_0_1000">↩</a>]</li>
  <li>What boundless hatred for Oracle? I don’t have a boundless hatred for Oracle! I keep my hatred for Oracle down to three hours a week <em>max</em>. [<a href="#identifier_1_1000">↩</a>]</li>
  <li>Only in the iTunes Store [<a href="#identifier_2_1000">↩</a>]</li>
  <li>I know she had nothing to do with Portal, but she’s got a nice voice and doesn’t get nearly enough air time these days. [<a href="#identifier_3_1000">↩</a>]</li>
  <li>The developer of Minecraft [<a href="#identifier_4_1000">↩</a>]</li>
  <li>This is a lie. All bloggers have huge egos. [<a href="#identifier_5_1000">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
