<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: announcement | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/announcement/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-26T10:01:38-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Thank You, Steve Jobs]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/10/thank-you-steve-jobs/"/>
    <updated>2011-10-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/10/thank-you-steve-jobs</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>We will miss you. This site wouldn’t exist without you, for what little that’s worth. Apple will carry on, and there will be wonderful advances based on what you did, but the world won’t be the same without you.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Salve atque vale.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>-Nate</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Dead Blogging the Apple Event Later Today.]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/dead-blogging-the-apple-event-later-today/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/dead-blogging-the-apple-event-later-today</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>Well, no, nobody’s dead. I’m just tired of calling it meta-live blogging or pseudo-live blogging or some such thing. So I came up with this really emo title instead. Now you’d think I’d come up with a  better title. But you’d be wrong. This is what we’re going with.</p>

<p> </p>

<p>The point is, Time-stamped hilarity is coming your way later today. I’m not dead. I think I’ll go for a walk.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New iPads Coming, Old iPads Attempting To Stay Calm]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/new-ipads-coming-old-ipads-attempting-to-stay-calm/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/new-ipads-coming-old-ipads-attempting-to-stay-calm</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>This just in:</p>

<p>[![the graphic from the iPad event invite][2]][2]
No, I wasn’t invited. Why would I be invited? I’m a nobody, man. </p>

<p>Expect people all over the world to start ditching their iPads in preparation for new iPads, and expect Android tablets to start wondering why they’re not competitive anymore[1][2] .<br />
Expect Tim Cook to try to be somewhere near as cool as The Steve. Expect a large number of superlatives from Jony Ive about the new device. Expect me to start subtly begging for money so I can buy one of the blasted things. <br />
And, as always, expect a not-exactly-live post from me covering the event in hard-to-follow detail.</p>

<p>[]: http://crazyapplenews.com/wp-content/uploads/2011/02/iPad-Invite-Graphic.jpg
 [2]: #footnote<em>0</em>1091 “not that they have ever really been competitive…”</p>

<p>We’ll be interviewing a current Gen iPad as soon as we find someone who is willing to let us talk to their iPad and not think it’s weird.</p>

<ol>
  <li>not that they have ever really been competitive… [<a href="#identifier_0_1091">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[John Moltz Joins Me In Hating John Mayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/john-moltz-joins-me-in-hating-john-mayer/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-02T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/john-moltz-joins-me-in-hating-john-mayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>Look, I’ve been publicly hating on John Mayer for a long time, now, and I didn’t get into the “Hate John Mayer” game just to get shown up by some upstart who’s been doing this a lot longer than I have. But what the heck, I like violent mood swings, so I’m happy to welcome<a href="http://crazyapplerumors.com/2011/02/02/apple-faces-new-suit/"> John Moltz into the Mayer-hating club</a> . We authors of CA*S sites that don’t update all that often have to stick together!</p>

<p>Someday, we can all be free of people who want to “run through the halls of [their] high school” and “break down the double doors.”</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Retroactive Official Break Notice]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/07/retroactive-official-break-notice/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-18T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/07/retroactive-official-break-notice</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>This is just to let you know that we are officially taking a break until this whole iPhone 4 thing blows over.<a href="#footnote_0_872" title="the past few weeks have been an unofficial break">1</a><br />
Because frankly, we’re tired of it. The only Apple news on the block is the iPhone 4. No new macs, no new iPods/iPads, or updates to OSX or any of the other stuff that is actually interesting or any fun. It’s all antennae and their problems, as far as the eye can see. It makes it hard to scrounge up material, especially if you’re as lazy as we are. It kinda goes like this:</p>

<p><strong>8:02:</strong> “Well, I’ll see what’s out there about Apple. Something funny must be happening”</p>

<p><strong>8:03:</strong> “Hmmm, Pogue thinks the iPhone is good. No surprise. Gruber thinks people who don’t think the iPhone is good are bad. Yep. Yep.”</p>

<table>
  <tbody>
    <tr>
      <td><strong>8:04</strong> “Would ‘the iPhone: Will it kill your entire family?’ be a good article? Bleh, no! C</td>
      <td>Net already did that one. Well, probably. It sounds like something they would do.”</td>
    </tr>
  </tbody>
</table>

<p><strong>8:06</strong> “Maybe I could start a ‘Crazy Windows News Site…wait, that’s Paul Therrot’s site. Too bad.”</p>

<p><strong>8:07</strong> “Maybe I should go into something less crazy.”</p>

<p>And that’s no way to run a humor site. So I will start writing funny things about things when something funny starts happening. Thank you very much.</p>

<ol>
  <li>the past few weeks have been an unofficial break [<a href="#identifier_0_872">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
