<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Meta | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/meta/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-05T13:09:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[From AR-CANS: iPhone 3GRS Review]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/07/from-ar-cans-iphone-3grs-review/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-19T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/07/from-ar-cans-iphone-3grs-review</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p><em>(The iPhone 4 thing is still raging out of control and making all Apple news in this universe really boring, mean-spirited, and depressing. So we are posting an article form AR-CANS, the Alternate Reality Crazy Apple News Site. They are writing about the new iPhone 3GRS<a href="#footnote_0_878" title="“RS” stands for “Really Speedy”">1</a> which was the follow-up to the 3G in their universe. Other than that, I’m told, their universe is pretty similar to ours.)</em></p>

<p>Many young fish have asked me if the 3GRS will be as airproof <em>and</em> gelatin-proof as it’s predecessor. There’s no denying that those weekend trips to Alpha Proxima were greatly facilitated by the aerophobic and geleophobic coatings Apple put on their iPhone flipper-held devices. But even with UniversCell technology, it seems that some calls were getting dropped in the outer reaches of the Oort cloud, where massive uncharted astral bodies could make it hard to get a signal. This of course explains the gelatin: anything submersed in gelatin has its signal strength boosted significantly, as you all know. this is why the Ensign, Gel-Class is such a coveted and enviable position on any starbus.</p>

<p>Well, the answer, my icthiods, is yes, the 3GRS retains the full body geleophobic coating that you have grown to love and trust in your flippertop app phone. Steve Cods assures us that the hypersolar market will be “the main audience” of all upcoming releases of the iPhone.</p>

<p>In other news, Microsoft doesn’t exist in this reality. But Linux lost another 2 percent of the shoal-top market, with Apple and BeOS picking up one percentage point apiece…</p>

<hr />

<p>Look, I gotta stop there. I was told these guys were pretty similar to us, but BeOS picking up market share? That’s just too weird.</p>

<ol>
<li>“RS” stands for “Really Speedy” [<a href="#identifier_0_878">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Outtakes From Friday&#8217;s iFAQ]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/06/outtakes-from-fridays-ifaq/"/>
    <updated>2010-06-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/06/outtakes-from-fridays-ifaq</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Since we actually got an iFAQ out the door on Friday we figured we’d celebrate by giving you a sneaky peek into the parts that don’t make it into the final edit, the footage that hits the cutting room floor. And hopefully by so doing we will also give you a greater appreciation for all the work we do around here while you’re out gallivanting around with your fancy friends.</p>

<p>Anyway, here’s the clips:<a href="#footnote_0_869" title="in your brain, the Horizontal Rules should sound like “boop”">1</a></p>

<ul>
<li><ul>
<li>*A: “And the Armadillo was all ‘yeah, but I just BOUGHT this shirt!”</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>[<em>Laughter</em>]</p>

<p>Q: Dude, everyone already knows that joke. It’s like, it’s a thousand years old.</p>

<p>Producer: Guys? We’re rolling.</p>

<p>Q: Crap! Right. Ahem. Hrm. Look, it’s a phone. It’s just a phone. What makes your [<em>starts laughing</em>] I just got it [<em>laughs</em>] He just BOUGHT that shirt!</p>

<hr />

<p>Q: Oh, yeah, that new iOS. It’s based on OS sex right?</p>

<p>[<em>Laughter from booth</em>]</p>

<p>Q: Whoa, forgot, I’m on CANS, not <a href="http://www.crazyapplerumors.com/?p=1231">CARS</a>.</p>

<p>A: What cat is THAT named after?</p>

<hr />

<p>A: The Retina Display has a surprisingly high pixel density, yes.</p>

<p>Q: …</p>

<p>A: Yes, very, very high.</p>

<p>Q: …</p>

<p>A: Lotsa pixels there.</p>

<p>Q: … Sorry, what? Oh yeah. It’s got glassy RAM or something, look, I was reading over next week’s script, and it got me all confused. Can we try again?</p>

<hr />

<p>Q: Dork.</p>

<p>A: Nerd.</p>

<p>Q: Jerkface.</p>

<p>A: Monkeyhead.</p>

<p>Producer: Guys? Can… can we get back to the script?</p>

<p>Q: Just a second, we’re almost done here. Windows User.</p>

<p>A: OS/2 Aficionado.</p>

<hr />

<p>A: Yep, it’s shtable, sholid, and hash more …. blerb bleoo bleh. Whoo! Let’s try that again.</p>

<p>[<em>Laughter</em>]</p>

<p>A: Need to warm up a bit. Blrblrblbrlblrb. “I saw a sheet a sheet I slit upon the slitted sheet I sit”<a href="#footnote_1_869" title="Pretty much the only thing I remember from Choir in High School. Yes I was in Choir in High School. Don’t judge me!">2</a> Okay, I’m good. Can we start again?</p>

<hr />

<p>A: Oooooh, them’s fightin’ words, pal.</p>

<p>Q: You wascaly wabbit!</p>

<p>[<em>Laughter</em>]</p>

<p>A: Whal Tarnation! My Biscuits are burnin’!</p>

<hr />

<p>A: Your Grandma.</p>

<p>Q: She runs Linux on a… dangit, what was it? A wolf pack? Something? Beowulf cluster? So it like, cuts the arms off of a WHOLE BUNCH of monsters? Okay, let’s go again. Sorry Grandma.</p>

<hr />

<p>And there you have it! We hope you enjoyed this little glimpse at life inside the iFAQ studio.</p>

<ol>
<li>in your brain, the Horizontal Rules should sound like “boop” [<a href="#identifier_0_869">↩</a>]</li>
<li>Pretty much the only thing I remember from Choir in High School. Yes I was in Choir in High School. Don’t judge me! [<a href="#identifier_1_869">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[New improved iPhone version of CANS]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/03/new-improved-iphone-version-of-cans/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-15T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/03/new-improved-iphone-version-of-cans</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Just a quick note to let all of you know that CANS now has a mobile version hosted right at crazyapplenews.com! So not only does it have the normal URI, but it also looks better and let’s you make comments! All for free! Give it a look-see next time you’re bored.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: What Happened in California]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/03/friday-ifaq-what-happened-in-california/"/>
    <updated>2010-03-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/03/friday-ifaq-what-happened-in-california</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy Apple user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>This week we answer the mysterious question: What the crap happened last week?</p>

<p>Q: So, what the crap did happen last week? You were all “I’m going to Cali, baby!” and nobody heard from you again.</p>

<p>A: Gaaah, I started that post like six times, but various computer glitches kept eating it, or scrambling the words, or some stupid thing. the most coherent thing to emerge from the wreckage was a comparison of my seat mate on the flight to a wildebeest.</p>

<p>Q: Weak. Sauce. Try. Harder.</p>

<p>A: Look, I’m not starting that post again, man. At one point the hard drive on my iMac self-destructed, and I had to take it into the shop for a new hard drive,<a href="#footnote_0_731" title="this actually happened. On the plus side my iMac now has a 1.5 TB hard drive">1</a> and when I rebuilt from my Time Machine backup my post was completely NOT on the backup.</p>

<p>Q: So those four of us who follow this blog are doomed to forever vaguely wonder if anything happened when you were in the home of the free Google Wi-fi?</p>

<p>A: Google Wi-fi rejected me. I wrote about that before the GREAT HARD DRIVE CRASH.</p>

<p>Q: So, you got anything for us?</p>

<p>A: Look, I feel bad, really I do, but writing about that trip is a curse. So instead I’ll just throw in something I wrote on that trip, that I was saving for your birthday.</p>

<p>Q: No, not gonna cut it.</p>

<h2>Ngmoco Buys Freeverse</h2>

<p>Q: And I get ignored again.</p>

<p>A: H2 tags can’t hear you. Now Shhhhh! the article’s starting.</p>

<p>We here at CANS HQ were distressed to learn that <a href="http://freeverse.com">Freeverse</a>, one of our favorite software vendors, from whom we have borrowed characters, is being purchased by Ngmoco, an iPhone game company. This news is odd, sad, and depressing, which is probably a good summation of the internet in general. But that’s beside the point.</p>

<p>Freeverse was our first introduction to mac games, with their Big Bang Board Games that shipped free on our iMac. The games were simple, but clean and Mac-like, with lots of polish and interaction. Over the years we found them to be equally excellent at other programs, from the actually useful Periscope<a href="#footnote_1_731" title="which I used as a security camera in my room in California">2</a> to the much needed port of Heroes of Might and Magic V to the Mac, we’ve relied on Freeverse to make easy-to-use, well designed software, and we’ve never been let down.</p>

<p>In recent years we’ve also done a very small amount of testing for Freeverse, and found their staff to be friendly, intelligent, and generous to a fault.</p>

<p>And now they’re being purchased by a company that formed, like, what? Three weeks ago? A company whose empire is based on Rolando: the story of a cartoon ball. This is kind of like some kid who just won a huge cash prize in a Risk tournament buying General Patton.</p>

<p>The question is: will they continue to make Mac games and programs? It seems unlikely. the iPhone/iPad platform is easier to write for, and has a huge base of people just waiting to devour your latest creation with minimal advertising. So desktop games and apps lose again on the mac and more people start to wonder if Windows is really all that bad.</p>

<p>Or maybe we’re blowing the whole thing out of proportion. (We are) so we’ll stop now. It’s not much, but we just wanted to thank Freeverse for the excellent games and wish them well in their new adventures. May the monkey ever be on your back.</p>

<ul>
<li><ul>
<li>*A: See! See? How was that, eh? Pathos, humor, nostalgia, that post has it all!</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>Q: Did you want to borrow some black nail polish emo-boy? Whiny. that’s what it was. Whiny.</p>

<p>A: Whatever man. That’s David Pogue level Pulitzer material.<a href="#footnote_2_731" title="I put that in just so David Pogue would read this and get mad at me again. Hey, negative attention is still attention! Ask any three-year-old!">3</a></p>

<p>Q: So, what we get from your trip to California is NOT EVEN a stupid T-Shirt, but a stupid article.</p>

<p>A: Okay, well, maybe you’ll like this post:</p>

<h2>MacHeist Mails it In</h2>

<p>Three months after the expected beginning of MacHeist, we get, not a new heist full of interest and prizes, but a cheap bundle of good but ininspiring software. Well, we here at CANS arent’ going to stand for it. I mean, yes we’ll buy the bundle, heck, we already have. But we’re not going to like it–</p>

<p>Q: Nope! Not interested.</p>

<p>A: Hey! Stop that!</p>

<p>Q: Alright look, you had a hard week, got it. I’m gonna go hang out with the Macalope for a while. Come back when you got something interesting to say.</p>

<ol>
<li>this actually happened. On the plus side my iMac now has a 1.5 TB hard drive [<a href="#identifier_0_731">↩</a>]</li>
<li>which I used as a security camera in my room in California [<a href="#identifier_1_731">↩</a>]</li>
<li>I put that in just so David Pogue would read this and get mad at me again. Hey, negative attention is still attention! Ask any three-year-old! [<a href="#identifier_2_731">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Not this week]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/01/not-this-week/"/>
    <updated>2010-01-31T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/01/not-this-week</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>No iFAQ this week, sorry. Monday is exactly one year since my sister-in-law died and I can’t think funny right now. Go drop by her site for a moment, if you like.</p>

<p>http://laurasteelmusic.com/</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
