<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: iPhone | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/iphone/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-08T15:53:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Next iPhone News Post]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/2013/04/08/next-iphone-news-post/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-08T14:51:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/2013/04/08/next-iphone-news-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="the-next-iphone-our-definitive-report">The Next iPhone: Our Definitive Report</h1>

<p>We here at CANS headquarters have been waiting for the new iPhone just as hard as anyone. Harder, even, because we are just that dedicated to this whole waiting thing.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>But we’re not just sitting around, resting on our laurels, knowing that we are the wait-hardest quasi-news source out there. Oh no. We have scoured the blogs and the articles and the sites that claim to have images of the casing that was most likely a prototype of the new iPhone charger casing, and through all of our research we are able to bring you, the CANS reader, a <em>definitive</em> list of factoids about the nascent iPhone. Enjoy.</p>

<h2 id="iphone-facts">iPhone Facts:</h2>

<ol>
  <li><strong>Release Date</strong>: every day April 15 to September 31 inclusive. “We’re doing it that way to keep the lines short” said an imaginary representative from Apple, Inc.</li>
  <li><strong>Supported Networks</strong>: All of them. Ever. And we really mean “every single network ever”. If you’ve still got an old Token-Ring LAN that needs BNC connectors to join up and transmits data at 15K baud, the new iPhone will let you place phone calls on this network. <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></li>
  <li><strong>Screen Size</strong>: 4.3721 inches diagonal. “Any other size will just look like crap,” says Sir Jony Ive, twitching slightly. “We’ve moved beyond <em>insanely great</em> to <em>insanely perfect</em>. And this is it. The best there is.” We thanked him for his time, but he interrupted with “what was that look? Don’t you believe me? Listen, when was the last time <em>you</em> were knighted solely on the strength of your industrial design skills?”</li>
  <li><strong>Turn by Turn Navigation</strong>: Look, we’re not talking about roads here. Siri will now give you moment-by-moment, turn-by-turn navigation for the treacherous waters of interpersonal relationships. Just ask your phone for the best possible response to comments like “you love that phone more than you love me” <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup>, and the only appropriate thing to say when asked if your significant other’s pants make them look fat <sup id="fnref:4"><a href="#fn:4" rel="footnote">4</a></sup>. </li>
  <li><strong>Price Point</strong>: Instead of a price “point” the new iPhone will be available along a pricing “gradient”, that takes several factors into account, such as how much money is in your bank account and… well, that’s pretty much it, actually. Oh, wait. Which network you’re on matters too. T-Mobile customers will pay something approaching a fair price, while AT&amp;T subscribers will continue to pay for their phone long after they actually paid it off. </li>
  <li><strong>Colors</strong>: The new iPhone will be available in black and not-quite-black. However, brand new iPhone “iCovers” will be available in all the colors you knew and loved as <a href="assets/socks.jpg">iPod socks</a>, because Apple still has a million of those things.</li>
  <li><strong>iOS 7</strong>: Yeah, probably. They might even give it the “massive overhaul” that the tech press claims they “need” to “keep ahead of Android”<sup id="fnref:5"><a href="#fn:5" rel="footnote">5</a></sup>. But we’re not holding our breaths. The one feature we expect to see is a completely redesigned Calendar app that is entirely flat and has the words “screw you, Forstall” emblazoned across every page of your calendar.</li>
</ol>

<p>So there you have it: CANS 100% definitive list of features you can expect from the new iPhone when it ships. You’re welcome.</p>

<div class="footnotes">
  <ol>
    <li id="fn:1">
      <p>Also because this is the first time that we’ve had the budget to actually <em>buy</em> an iPhone.<a href="#fnref:1" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:2">
      <p>Of course, the lightning-BNC adapter will cost several thousand dollars.<a href="#fnref:2" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:3">
      <p>“Of course I don’t honey. I love my phone <em>exactly as much</em> as I love you!”<a href="#fnref:3" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:4">
      <p>Your phone will send you a text message informing you of the near death of a beloved relative.<a href="#fnref:4" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
    <li id="fn:5">
      <p>Have you <em>used</em> Android 4.2? It’s <em>amazing!</em><a href="#fnref:5" rel="reference">&#8617;</a></p>
    </li>
  </ol>
</div>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
