<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Inside Apple | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/inside-apple/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-26T17:09:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Overheard in the Boardroom: Preparing for WWDC]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/overheard-in-the-boardroom-preparing-for-wwdc/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-05T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/overheard-in-the-boardroom-preparing-for-wwdc</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p><strong>Tim Cook</strong>: Listen, guys, we’ve got to get this right.</p>

<p><strong>Phil Schiller</strong>: Okay, sorry, Tim. We’re ready this time.</p>

<p><strong>Cook</strong>: Good. Okay, one, two, three, four!</p>

<p><strong>Peter Oppenheimer</strong>: A-wheem a way, a wheem a way…</p>

<p><strong>Jony Ive</strong>: In the iMac, the peaceful iMac, Lion’s been installed!</p>

<p><strong>Scott Forstall</strong>: De-we-um-um-a-way!</p>

<p><strong>Ive</strong>: On the MacBook, the 13” MacBook, Lion’s been installed!</p>

<p><strong>Forstall</strong>: WEEEEEEEEEE-de-de-de a Whum-a-way!</p>

<p><strong>Schiller</strong>: Hush my darling, iOS and Lion, share lots of good ideas. Full-screen apps and, gestures for actions, make Lion excellent!</p>

<p><strong>Forstall</strong>: Hey! Hey! Whoa-a-wo! Whoa-a-wo a Wheem-o-whum-whum-a-way!</p>

<p><strong>Schiller</strong>: Wait, wait, Tim, he’s doing it again.</p>

<p><strong>Cook</strong>: What’s wrong Phil?</p>

<p><strong>Schiller:</strong> Scott keeps singing his weem-o-whum-a-ways over the top of my words.</p>

<p><strong>Ive:</strong> Also, I only have one line, despite the fact that I’m the best looking of us.</p>

<p><strong>Forstall:</strong> I’m angry that my verse about beta testers being amazing was cut!</p>

<p><strong>John Mayer: </strong>I’m mad that I’m not invited to sing at these events any more</p>

<p><strong>Cook: </strong>Who let lizard boy in here? [on intercom] Security! John Mayer broke in again.</p>

<p><strong>Oppenheimer:</strong> I still think it should be pronounced “Wheem o whip!”</p>

<p><strong>Forstall:</strong> Look, Pete, we’ve been over this. That’s clearly not how you say it—</p>

<p><strong>Schiller:</strong> Why are we worrying about how you say it? We should just worry about the fact that Scott keeps singing over my lines!</p>

<p><em>[everyone starts talking at once. Jony Ive seems to just be saying “rhubarb, rhubarb!” over and over again]</em></p>

<p><strong>Cook: </strong>Listen, Listen! Guys, we’ve got to get this right!</p>

<p><strong>Schiller: </strong>Okay, sorry, Tim. We’re ready this time.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
