<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: writing | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/writing/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-05T13:09:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Ulysses]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/2013/04/05/friday-ifaq-ulysses/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-05T13:05:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/2013/04/05/friday-ifaq-ulysses</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy Apple user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>This week we're getting our iFAQ muscles back in shape and talking about Ulysses III, the all-in-one authoring tool that--</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: AAAAAAAUGH [<em>Runs and tackles the narrator</em>]</p>

<p><strong>Narrator</strong>: Ouch! Dang it! Look, hey, get off! What're you doing?</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Who are you and what have you done with the real author?</p>

<p><strong>N</strong>: What are you talking about? It's me! Remember? From before?</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Look, you're not him I mean, you're doing this article on <em>Ulysses</em> for Pete's sake, and you're, you know, actually writing posts. These don't sound like the guy who <a href="http://crazyapplenews.com/2010/10/friday-ifaq-scrivener-2-0/" title="Friday iFAQ Scrivener 2.0">once said</a> that "Ulysses interface makes rats barf."</p>

<p><strong>N</strong>: Look, people change. Software changes. The world moves on, and the Soulmen actually did a pretty great job with Ulysses III.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So that's it? You wander off for a few years, leave me to languish, and all I get when you come back is "people change and Ulysses is pretty good now!"? Not okay, man, not okay.</p>

<p><strong>N</strong>: But it's gonna be okay. We're on a new host now, with fewer bugs and problems and stuff, and we're ready to crank this thing out old school style.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Well… I don't know if I can really trust you…</p>

<p><strong>N</strong>: Give me a chance. Please? For old times?</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Okay. You've got one shot at this.</p>

<p><strong>N</strong>: Thanks. Okay, I'm turning it over to <strong>A</strong> now.</p>

<h2>Friday iFAQ: Ulysses. F'real this time.</h2>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So, Ulysses? <em>Really?</em> I can't believe we're doing this. What's so new and special that we're changing our sitewide hatred for that program?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, in a word, <em>everything.</em> The company that makes Ulysses has rebuilt it from the ground up. All the old, weird features are gone and replaced with surprisingly solid new features.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Like what?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: The interface, for starters. The old interface was, well, it had Pre-OSX roots, and they were quite visible. The new app is sleek, clean, and polished.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: You used to say nice things like that about <a href="http://www.literatureandlatte.com/scrivener.php" title="Scrivener 2.0, the world's best creative writing software ever.">Scrivener</a>.</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Scrivener is still our main choice for long form writing. But It's not a "this or that" situation. Both apps have their purposes. Ulysses is much better for just getting thoughts down quickly, without worrying too much about the formatting or the layout or having a title or what folder this new text should go into.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So it's <a href="http://brettterpstra.com/projects/nvalt/" title="nvALT: fork of Notational Velocity">nvALT</a>, but for money?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: There are similarities. But Ulysses has a lot of refinements that aren't in nvALT. You're not limited to a single directory, or even a single platform. You can sync via iCloud and/or Dropbox, or just keep the files on your local system.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So that's it? Just ditch Brett Terpstra altogether?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Definitely not. Look, Ulysses isn't perfect. They've made some odd choices as regards the file storage mechanism; it doesn't handle MultiMarkdown natively, previewing your text in <a href="http://markedapp.com/" title="Marked, an amazing way to preview markdown texts">Marked</a> is strangely difficult… but it's a lot of massive steps in the right direction.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Well…does it still make rats barf?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Even Jony Ive would love the interface now. It looks a lot like iTunes 11.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Alright then.</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: See? Just like old times!</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Your banter is a bit off.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
