<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Phone calls | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/phone-calls/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-04-08T15:53:55-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[On the Phone: Steve Jobs and John Mayer]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2008/09/on-the-phone-steve-jobs-and-john-mayer/"/>
    <updated>2008-09-13T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2008/09/on-the-phone-steve-jobs-and-john-mayer</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1 id="section"></h1>

<p>So, while I was chatting with Steve Jobs on the phone after the “Let’s Rock” event he received a call from John Mayer. I don’t know if he meant to put it on three-way calling, or if he just meant to put me on hold, but this is a transcript of the call:</p>

<p><em>Phone rings</em></p>

<p><strong>Jobs</strong>: Oh crap.  I gotta take this, Moltz. Hold on.</p>

<p><strong>Dickson</strong>: Er, Dickson, actually. But Moltz is fine.</p>

<p><strong>Mayer</strong>: Hey Steve.</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Hi John.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: I saw the keynote today.</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Good, good.</p>

<p>M: You played “Gravity” as a “Genius” example. That was pretty cool.</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Glad you liked that.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: And some of my other songs came up as well.</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Yep.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: But I was surprised, there at the end, when that Hawaiian guy got up on stage.</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Jack Johnson is a very talented artist, and…</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: I had my guitar there with me, Steve.  I was already to go.  What happened?</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Look, John, I know this might be hard for you, but we’ve moved on.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: Moved on? You can’t leave me, Steve! You need me! Apple needs me!</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: John, don’t make this harder than it already is. Bono didn’t get all whiny like this when we stopped making the U2 special edition iPod.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: What about that one keynote? And that other keynote? I rocked the house!</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: You performed adequately, yes, but…</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: I mean, I can understand bringing in Randy Newman from time to time. You basically own his soul, right?</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Well, Pixar did, which means Disney does, so basically yes, but…</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: So he’s okay; he’s fine. But Jack Johnson? Some wimpy hyper-mellow…</p>

<p><strong>D</strong>: Maybe I should just go…</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Quiet, Moltz.</p>

<p><strong>D</strong>: Dickson. But Moltz is fine!</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Whatever. Listen, John, your time has passed. You’ll still show up in cover flows or as a “favorite song” in a playlist here or there but your star has set.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: What’s that Johnson got that I don’t got?</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: Grammar, for one.  Also, he’s personable, John. He tells jokes. He connects with the audience.</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: I can tell jokes! I can connect!</p>

<p><strong>J</strong>: You look like a stuffed iguana trying to sing, John. Let’s face it. You were hot for a while because of that real world song, and that wonderland song, but…(<em>tinny snippet of “<a href="http://www.jackjohnsonmusic.com/music/detail/curious_george_ost">Upside Down</a>” starts playing</em>) Look, John, it’s over. Goodbye. And Moltz, I told you stop calling me. (<em>click</em>)</p>

<p><strong>D</strong>: Dickson… Oh who cares. (<em>to self</em>) I could never be as good as John Moltz…</p>

<p><strong>M</strong>: (<em>to self</em>) I could never be as good as Jack Johnson…</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
