<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Friday iFAQ | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/friday-ifaq/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-26T17:09:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Bowtie]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/friday-ifaq-bowtie/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-22T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/friday-ifaq-bowtie</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy <a href="http://apple.com">Apple</a> user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>This week we seek for some solace in nostalgia with the advent of <a href="http://bowtieapp.com/">Bowtie</a>, a skinnable iTunes controller.</p>

<p>Q: A What-able what now? What is the madness you are saying with your face?</p>

<p>A: Oh, come on, we were all there. Remember the early 2000’s when you were finally able to play music on your computer, and you had all these cool skins for your music player?</p>

<p>Q: No.</p>

<p>A: Sure you do. You could make it look like a brain, and the buttons were made out of wrinkles on the brain’s surface, or you could have it look like a big piano with the control buttons outlined on the keys, or whatever.</p>

<p>Q: Nope!</p>

<p>A: Wow, did you miss out. All the music players did it. Windows Media Player, Winamp, RealPlayer…</p>

<p>Q: All windows programs you’ll notice.</p>

<p>A: Er, well, see, I didn’t get my first mac until 2006, so…</p>

<p>Q: Well, for those of us who have always used good computers we’ve used boring, gray old iTunes and liked it. We don’t need your silly skinnable thingies.</p>

<p>A: But look, you’ve got a chance now! Bowtie is free in the Mac App Store, and you can have a little player that shows you what album you’re listening to, has all your controls, and is really really out of the way AND cool looking, all at the same time!</p>

<p>Q: I don’t really see the point…</p>

<p>A: AND it lets you love or ban songs on Last.fm, so people know what you think about the music you’re listening to! That’s something we couldn’t do back in the day, back with dumb ol’ web 1.0</p>

<p>Q: So there really isn’t a point.</p>

<p>A: The point is to have fun! Come on, it’s spring! The sky is bright, life is good, maybe you should loosen up a bit too! Sometimes things can just be fun. I’m using it to listen to the Tron: Legacy soundtrack right now, just because I can!</p>

<p>Q: Hmmm, not sure I can lower my standards of “fun” quite that far.</p>

<p>A: *sigh*. Okay, Mr. Boring Pants. Go watch your news programs and listen to your collection of the 100 greatest renditions of <em>4'.33"</em> I’ll catch you later.</p>

<p>Q: What’s wrong with <em><a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/4'33%22">4'33"</a></em>?</p>

<p>A: Oh, it’s nothing.<a href="#footnote_0_1119" title="I couldn’t resist">1</a></p>

<ol>
<li>I couldn’t resist [<a href="#identifier_0_1119">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Twitter for Mac]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/friday-ifaq-twitter-for-mac/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-08T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/friday-ifaq-twitter-for-mac</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>This week, it’s all about Twitter’s creatively named Twitter client: Twitter for Mac <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#stupidname">#stupidname</a> <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/Ilikehashtags">#Ilikehashtags</a></p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So what’s the big deal with Twitter in the first place? Lots of short messages flying around all over the place, forcing people to abbrev</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Ah, so we’re doing that, are we? all our questions and answers have to be less than 140 characters?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Yep! It’ll help you stop whinging( on about stupid crap. <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#justsayin">#justsayin</a></p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: So the point is to get us all to distill the essence of what we want to say, to refine our thinking and use every letter effectively?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, I think originally it was just because that was the length of a standard text message. <a href="http://twitter.com/Pogue">@Pogue</a> would know. He’s like, a Twitter god.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: 138, 139, 140. Wow, you’re way too good at getting EXACTLY 140 characters in there. Should I be scared?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Why? It’s just a way to communicate with people, and get a sense of what’s going on in the world around us.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Okay, whatever. I’m going to allow–for the moment–that Twitter has validity as a form of communication. But why do I need an app?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, it makes it easier to see what’s happened in your feed, post replies…</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Easier than going to a web site? That does the exact same thing?</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, for one thing, the app wastes far less screen space with stupid things like <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#trendingtopics">#trendingtopics</a>. Seriously, I hate those.</p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: And yet you linked to a discussion about them. Odd.</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Yeah, sorry about that. It gets to be a habit after a while. <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#Ijustcannotstopmyself">#Ijustcannotstopmyself</a></p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Yeah, I’m still not sold. Not just on the client either. I don’t see a real point for Twitter in general.</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: Well, there’s not much I can say to change your mind. It’s all free, so you can try it out, see if you like it.</p>

<p><strong>A</strong>: The name is very appropriate: there’s a lot of tweets, like birds in a tree, but they’re all really short and not a big deal. <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#nobigdeal">#nobigdeal</a></p>

<p><strong>Q</strong>: Almost thou convincest me to become a…what exactly? Tweeter? Twit? Bird?</p>

<p>A: Yeah, nobody’s really sure. <a href="http://twitter.com/#!/search/#ohwell">#ohwell</a>.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Hordes of Orcs 2]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/friday-ifaq-hordes-of-orcs-2/"/>
    <updated>2011-03-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/03/friday-ifaq-hordes-of-orcs-2</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy <a href="http://apple.com">Apple</a> user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>This week we pay a visit to the land of one of our favorite made up correspondents, Grug the Orc. Grug is sporting a shiny new interface in the <a href="http://www.freeverse.com/mac/product/?id=9023">update</a> to his native land of…What is your native land called, Grug?</p>

<p>A: Grug not know. We call it “wooden gate”.</p>

<p>Q: So tell us, what makes Hordes of Orcs 2 such a great new addition to the H.o.O. dynasty?</p>

<p>A: This just sick, you know.</p>

<p>Q: Why?</p>

<p>A: Why you ask Grug about new ways to kill Grug’s family?</p>

<p>Q: Family. Really.</p>

<p>A: Well, all us orcs instances of same class. It like family!</p>

<p>Q: So, asking you about the new and improved gameplay feels a bit heartless then?</p>

<p>A: What improved? Now player can use big railgun to kill orcs. But orcs still not fight back much.</p>

<p>Q: You’re not really selling the product there, Grug.</p>

<p>A: Grug feel deep sense of orc pride, not want to send more members of family into trenches.</p>

<p>Q: I guess we can respect that. So…let’s talk about something else, then?</p>

<p>A: Okay. It your website. What questions you have?</p>

<p>Q: Ummm…what do you do in your spare time?</p>

<p>A: Grug teaching self to use ray tracing software. Make computer still life pictures.</p>

<p>Q: Huh. Well, that’s interesting. What have you done so far?</p>

<p>A: Oh you know, made a teapot, made a sphere on a column, a human getting shot by a lightning tower, all the basics.</p>

<p>Q: Riiiight.</p>

<p>A: Sometimes Grug suspects he has rage issues that need worked out.</p>

<p>Q: Well that’s all the time we have…</p>

<p>A: Grug never knew his parent class! Grug an orphan!</p>

<p>Q: Join us next time for more iFAQ’s and less…orc emotion.</p>

<p>A: Grug so lonely! All Grug ever wanted was a friend!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Thunderbolt]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/friday-ifaq-thunderbolt/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-25T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/friday-ifaq-thunderbolt</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy Apple user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>this week we talk about the newest thing in physical IO: LightPeak Thunderbolt!</p>

<p> </p>

<p>Q: So, What makes Thunderbolt better than other stuff?</p>

<p>A: Speed. Pure, unbridled fastness. Faster than fast, and daisy-chainable, Thunderbolt is–</p>

<p>Q: a lot like Firewire. You know, Apple’s last failed attempt at pushing a new IO specification on all of us. All they do is force LaCie to make a few hard drives that are outlandishly expensive because they use non-standard ports.</p>

<p>A: Firewire isn’t a failed technology! It’s just not…fully embraced.</p>

<p>Q: What about ExpressCard?</p>

<p>A: ExpressCard…could have done better, sure, but–</p>

<p>Q: And Firewire</p>

<p>A: you already said that one.</p>

<p>Q: Ah, but I was talking about Firewire 800 this time.</p>

<p>A: Okay,well, yeah, Firewire 800 hasn’t really taken off, athough there are people that use it.</p>

<p>Q: We’ll call them “People who use macs to make movies” and move on.</p>

<p>A: It’s not Just…okay, fair enough. But Thunderbolt is–</p>

<p>Q: A lot like the <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Apple_Display_Connector">ADC</a>?</p>

<p>A: We don’t talk about the ADC around here.</p>

<p>Q: Face it, Apple makes a lot of amazing technology, but they just don’t drive hardware standards. Pretty much every connector they champion ends up in second place. Look at DisplayPort.</p>

<p>A: Hey, now, you can’t call DisplayPort a failed connector yet! It’s still in the works! Dell is using it! Lots of people are using it!</p>

<p>Q: To connect to Apple Cinema Displays.</p>

<p>A: Right. No! To connect to all kinds of high end monitors. And besides, what about all the changes that Apple has made? What about the death of the Floppy drive? or the death of the stylus?</p>

<p>Q: Granted, they’re good at showing the world what our hardware should do, or rather, what it should stop doing. I mean, using a stylus, remember that?</p>

<p>A: Always losing it, trying to get your finger to be precise enough on those terrible resistive displays…</p>

<p>Q: Or using a ballpoint pen lid, because if you used the actual pen you’d get your screen all covered in ink.</p>

<p>A: Yeah, those were the terrible old days. Learning some new way to write so it would more-or-less understand your handwriting–</p>

<p>Q: But of course, half the time you just gave up and used the on-screen keyboard.</p>

<p>A: Well sure, it was faster to hunt and peck than scratch and swear.</p>

<p>Q: Yep, yep. Well, I guess Apple has made a difference after all.</p>

<p>A: That’s right.</p>

<p>Q: Be that as it may, Thunderbolt still isn’t going to ever be popular.</p>

<p>A: …I know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Friday iFAQ: Cinch]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/friday-ifaq-cinch/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-04T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/friday-ifaq-cinch</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every Friday we publish a list of inFrequently Answered Questions and answers to help you, the Crazy Apple user, get more out of your Crazy Apple products.</p>

<p>Today we throw some fuel on the eternal flamewar and review Cinch, the program that Apple should have thought of first.</p>

<p>Q: So, I have a problem. It’s, well, it’s all my windows.</p>

<p>A: Go on.</p>

<p>Q: They’re not bad, you understand. That is, they mean well, you see.</p>

<p>A: I understand.</p>

<p>Q: But, well, they’re a bit unruly from time to time.</p>

<p>A: They start sitting on top of each other, that sort of thing?</p>

<p>Q: Exactly. Like, XCode will lean just enough to cover a column of text in my browser window, or Chrome will be just big enough to Obscure iTunes’ controls, that sort of thing.</p>

<p>A: So, it’s not enough for you to actually get mad, at them, because they’re not actually doing anything wrong, but they’re definitely acting up a bit.</p>

<p>Q: Yeah. I’ve tried putting them in different <a href="http://www.apple.com/macosx/what-is-macosx/apps-and-utilities.html#spaces">Spaces</a>, you know, so that Chrome is in 1 and XCode is in 2, and that keeps them from touching each other, but it gets to be a real pain running back and forth all the time, know what I mean?</p>

<p>A: Some days it feels like that’s all you do, running back and forth from one program to the next, each one bouncing their icon at you, trying to get your attention.</p>

<p>Q: You’ve seen this sort of behavior before, I see.</p>

<p>A: I’ve got programs too, my friend. I understand what you’re going through.</p>

<p>Q: Well, what’s worked for you? How do you keep your programs in line? I mean, it seems like this is a pretty common problem.</p>

<p>A: There’s a great new app in the Mac App Store that takes care of just this problem. It’s called <a href="http://itunes.apple.com/us/app/cinch/id412529613?mt=12">Cinch</a>, and it’s exactly what you need.</p>

<p>Q: How does it work?</p>

<p>A: With Cinch installed, you just drag a window’s title bar to the edge of the screen to make that window take up exactly one half of your display. Drag a window to the other side and you’ve got two nicely lined-up windows, not touching each other, just sharing an edge.</p>

<p>Q: So I can look at things in Chrome while I work in XCode!</p>

<p>A: Exactly my friend.</p>

<p>Q: That’s a seriously great idea! Why hasn’t anyone made this <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-7/features/snap.aspx">part of their operating system</a> yet?</p>

<p>A: It’s a mystery. One more thing, by the way. Let’s say you want one app to take full screen. All you do is drag it’s title bar up to the top of the screen and BAM! Full screen mode.</p>

<p>Q: That’s great. But what if I want to put everything back where it was?</p>

<p>A: Just drag the windows back to the middle of the screen and they’ll resize back to what they looked like before you Cinched them up.</p>

<p>Q: That is some seriously intuitive and useful user interface work. What kind of genius <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/windows/windows-7/features/snap.aspx">came up with that</a>, I wonder?</p>

<p>A: We may never know.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
