<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Editorial | Crazy Apple News Site]]></title>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/blog/categories/editorial/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-26T17:09:11-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Nate Dickson]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[XCode 4 in the App Store: Apple&rsquo;s April Fool&rsquo;s Day Joke]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/xcode-4-in-the-app-store-apples-april-fools-day-joke/"/>
    <updated>2011-04-01T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/04/xcode-4-in-the-app-store-apples-april-fools-day-joke</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>At first, it just doesn’t make sense. <a href="http://apple.com">Apple</a> is selling, <em>selling</em> XCode, that amazing—and previously free—programmer’s delight of an IDE that is the gateway to the riches of putting your programs in the App Stores.</p>

<p>Don’t get me wrong, XCode 4 is a massive improvement on the previous versions, with everything integrated into a single window, a massive improvement on the previous versions’ tendency to spread windows over your entire desktop and eventually into other Spaces, just because there are so dang many of them. The new debugger is faster, more intuitive, gives you good stack traces, even on multiple threads, and actually tries to trace your local variables and display them in a way that makes sense to humans, again something at which XCode 3 struggled.</p>

<p>So many of us purchased XCode 4 from the app store, telling ourselves that, considering how much Windows developers pay for <a href="http://www.microsoft.com/visualstudio/en-us/products/2010-editions/premium">Visual Studio</a> we were getting off easy. And we downloaded the 4.5 Gigabyte file, and we ran the installer, and everything was good. XCode 4 was installed! Life was happy. Blithely we deleted the Installer file that the App Store dropped into our Applications folders and started tinkering around with all the new features, like Git integration and a useful timeline view of code changes and whatnot.</p>

<p>Then, a few days later, Apple released version 4.0.1 of the app. Well, we had noticed a few things that were kinda buggy with the initial release, so that’s to be expected. We go into the App Store, expecting an upgrade notification and…nothing. The App Store says we haven’t installed XCode 4. But look! It’s running right there! Lo and behold, deleting the 4.5 Gigabyte installer file from our Applications folder is what told the App Store that we no longer had XCode on our drive. So we download the new version—all 4.5 Gigabytes of it—and reinstall. The awful truth dawns slowly: we have to keep that stupid installer file to get our “convenient” automatic updates.</p>

<p>This, I feel, is too coincidental. It is clearly a joke, played upon the Apple developer community and their ISP’s. Apple is too smart to saddle their developers with a gigantic dead weight file and massive downloads for every patch release. Fortunately, they’ve given us some clues. Look at the version number: <strong>4.0.1</strong>. Does that suggest anything to you? Looks a lot like 4/1, doesn’t it? Yep, it’s an April Fool’s day joke.</p>

<p>Okay, Apple, you’ve had your fun. Now let’s make with version 4.0.2 getting rid of the annoyance factors. I’ve got better uses for that huge chunk of hard drive space. Thank you.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[An Office Haiku]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/an-office-haiku/"/>
    <updated>2011-02-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2011/02/an-office-haiku</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>[![A shadow that seems to be pixelated][2]][2]</p>

<p>Sunlight and shadow,<br/>
Through venetian blinds, my world<br/>
Looks pixelated.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[2010: The Year We Make Contact. With iPads]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/12/2010-the-year-we-make-contact-with-ipads/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/12/2010-the-year-we-make-contact-with-ipads</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>2010 has been a big year for those of us who write things about Apple Products. It’s been a busy year for Apple, with a groundbreaking new product, a fiasco-riddled update to an existing product, and millions upon millions of new dollars flowing into their coffers. Join me as we look at some of the events of 2010 through the lens of hindsight and minimal research. As usual, we start with</p>

<p><strong>January</strong></p>

<p>Most of January was spent rampantly speculating about what Apple would be announcing at their Big Reveal event on the 27th. As it became more and more certain that some sort of Tablet was in the works the Mythical Apple Tablet became the focus of everyone’s imagination. Feature lists sprang up like Peashooters in Plants vs. Zombies<a href="#footnote_0_1031" title="which was also quite popular at the time">1</a> and everyone was, well, kinda disappointed when the device that was actually revealed turned out to be a very intelligently designed, sensible device at a surprisingly low price. However, once the iPad was announced we of the Apple press were left facing the question of what we should write about in</p>

<p><strong>February</strong></p>

<p>With the iPad announced but not released, we had a lot of time to try and figure out what, if anything, was coming next. Apple itself seemed to be entirely focused on getting the iPad right, and we didn’t even get any good rumors during the shortest and bleakest month. Nate went to California, and subsequently failed to write anything interesting about the trip, as his computer committed suicide every time he tried to work up a post. I’ll say this: it was very warm. Which sounds nice right now. December in SLC is bitter, bitter. But things warmed up in</p>

<p><strong>March</strong></p>

<p>With the announcement that <a href="http://store.steampowered.com/">Steam </a>would be coming to the Mac. People wondered why it was that Apple let Valve beat them to the online software distribution punch. In other Apple news, the iPad still wasn’t released, and people continued the “big iPod Touch” jokes, and the “pad sounds like a feminine hygiene product” jokes, neither of which were funny.</p>

<p>In CANS news, “Q” spent March standing in line to buy an iPad, which was finally released in</p>

<p><strong>April</strong></p>

<p>The month of the iPad! It was finally here! It was real! Everyone wanted one! Little kids hugged them! It was like Christmas! The dang things were actually really good! There’s really nothing bad to say about the iPad launch. It went off well and the iPad was and is an amazing device. And it’s good that iPad news was so positive, because April is also the month of the iPhone 4 fiasco.</p>

<p>It’s old news, but still irritating. Gizmodo bought a prototype iPhone 4 from a guy who picked it up in a bar when someone left it there…you know the song. Anyway, this happened in April, and like any terrible news story, was still making waves in</p>

<p><strong>May</strong></p>

<p>We decided to spend May entirely inwardly focused, as “Q” was still weak from his exposure to the elements and we really hated all the negativity about the iPhone 4. We had our own run-in with negativity on our other blog when we thoughtlessly said some rude things about Roger Ebert. But out in Apple-world the iPhone 4 storm swirled on into</p>

<p><strong>June</strong></p>

<p>When the iPhone 4 was actually really announced to a not-very-surprised world. The Retina display is and</p>

<p>[![Apple Mac Mini 2010 Edition][4]][4]
Little. Aluminum. Different.</p>

<p>was an amazing idea, and this was before we knew the antennae on the device were flawed. The new Mac Mini was announced and Steve Jobs posted some thoughts about Flash. Adobe responded with typical aplomb, by which I mean various Adobe personnel told Apple where they could stick their magical devices. But, the Mac Mini, that was and is a thing of wonder. Or at least it’s really tiny and beautiful. But beauty isn’t everything, and in</p>

<p><strong>July</strong></p>

<p>We learned that form has to follow function as the iPhone 4 was officially launched and people discovered that wrapping their hands around the thing in certain ways reduced your signal strength. We here at CANS tried to ignore this whole mess then, and we continue to do so now. In July we heard from the future, the past, and an alternate reality, all to avoid “Antennagate” and it’s repercussions. Fortunately Apple announced a new battery charger at the end of July, so the month wasn’t a total loss. And speaking of loss, in</p>

<p><strong>August</strong></p>

<p>Apple lost their most interestingly named executive, Mr. Papermaster. We here at CANS felt the loss keenly, as we hadn’t made nearly enough jokes based on that name. I mean, look at it. Papermaster. Paper<em>master</em>. It’s just too good. But he’s gone and there’s nothing we can do about it. So we’re back to jokes about Phil Schiller. Ah well. Anyway, August segued right into</p>

<p><strong>September</strong></p>

<p>with the announcement of a big music event at which Apple announced all kinds of new iPods. the new iPod Touch should really be called the iPad Mini, and the new Nano should be called the iPod Shuffle Touch. An updated Apple TV was announced, and people still seem to feel that it’s got a long way to go before it reaches its full potential. And in</p>

<p><strong>October</strong></p>

<p><a href="#footnote_1_1031" title=" Look, you try coming up with 12 really good segues "><img src="#footnote_1_1031" title=" Look, you try coming up with 12 really good segues " alt="MacBook Air" /></a>We were told that the potential for a new version of OSX was about to become a reality. Well, actually, Lion isn’t due to ship until “Summer 2011″, but we got a sneak peek at what Apple’s working on. The “Back to the Mac” theme that they chose for the announcement event was, it turned out, more meaningful than we expected, as many UI decisions and idioms from the iPad are being brought back to the Mac, from which, Apple was quick to remind us, iOS originally came. Chief amongst these is a Mac App Store, which will let you buy your Mac Apps without going to real stores or the actual internet or anything. the App Store is set to launch in just a few days, well ahead of the rest of the Lion package. Seemingly designed specifically for Lion, Apple also released the new MacBook Air, which is so small it’s practically an iPad itself. Whether people will buy into it or not is anyone’s guess. Then it was</p>

<p><strong>November </strong><a href="#footnote_1_1031" title=" Look, you try coming up with 12 really good segues ">2</a></p>

<p>The month were I wrote a book, as I am wont to do. But even so, Apple wasn’t content to rest on their laurels. No, they finally put the axe to the XServe and buried the hatchet with Apple Corps. For the first time ever, it became possible to buy Beatles music on iTunes. Someday I might actually do so. But don’t hold your breath. And indeed, we were all breathing fairly easily heading into</p>

<p><strong>December</strong></p>

<p>Where Apple announced the early launch of the App Store, which won’t happen until next month. Many, many people got iPads as holiday presents, which of course means that it’s time to start speculating about the iPad 2′s specs and pricing.</p>

<p>And that’s 2010 in a nutshell. What will 2011 hold? Will the App Store for Mac take off like a rocket to the moon or fizzle out like that Ping thing that’s built into iTunes 10? Will Lion be everything we were hoping for and more? Will Penny and Leonard get back together, or are they going to pull a Ross and Rachael right up until the final episode of The Big Bang Theory?<a href="#footnote_2_1031" title="The parallels between Friends and TBBT are striking. It’s almost as if the producers of TBBT realized that they had a good ensemble sitcom on their hands and decided to do some research into how those work out…">3</a> We can but wait and see. And speculate wildly, of course. But that’s the subject for another post. Here’s to the year that was.</p>

<ol>
<li>which was also quite popular at the time [<a href="#identifier_0_1031">↩</a>]</li>
<li>Look, you try coming up with 12 really good segues [<a href="#identifier_1_1031">↩</a>]</li>
<li>The parallels between Friends and TBBT are striking. It’s almost as if the producers of TBBT realized that they had a good ensemble sitcom on their hands and decided to do some research into how those work out… [<a href="#identifier_2_1031">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Annual CANS Failed Holiday Poetry Post!]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/12/the-annual-cans-failed-holiday-poetry-post/"/>
    <updated>2010-12-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/12/the-annual-cans-failed-holiday-poetry-post</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>Every year I try to come up with a clever post, that takes some classic poem and turns it into a bunch of stuff that has to do with all the Apple News we’ve seen over the previous year. And every year it turns into something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>Once upon a midnight dreary,<br/>
As I pondered weak and weary<br/>
Over many quaint and curious iPhone<br/>
Bought in days of yore</p></blockquote>

<p>and then before I get to the part where they’ll get upgraded “nevermore” I realize that I’m supposed to be trying to do a Christmas/Hanukkah/Kwanzaa/New Years/Saturnalia type poem, not a Halloween one. So then I try again with something like this:</p>

<blockquote><p>The moon on the crest of the new-fallen snow<br/>
Glared like an iPad in in full sunlight below.<br/>
And Jobs in his kerchief, and Ive in his cap,<br/>
had just counted their money and an intern did slap<a href="#footnote_0_1020" title="Being me I would try to work a “fired. Out of a cannon” joke in here, but it really doesn’t scan at all.">1</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Which invariably gets pretty terrible.</p>

<p>I had good luck with the letters to Santa Jobs one year, which were fun to write and gave me a lot of latitude to make fun of all manner of people in concise and amusing ways. But doing that again would be basically admitting that I’m completely out of ideas.</p>

<p>So then I’ll try for the sentimental angle, thanking people for all their support over the past year, which really has been pretty great. Or I’ll drop hints about my upcoming “predictions for next year” post, which guarantees that said post will never get written. But I’ve decided I’m not going to do any of that this year.</p>

<p>Well, except for the “thank you” part. Seriously, thank you all for reading. You make this worth doing.</p>

<p>But other than that, I’m not doing any of the stuff I usually do. Instead, I’m trying something new this year. This year I’m going to write a short story. Like, just abandon the journalistic overtones and do some full-on fiction. It’ll be fun! And it doesn’t have to rhyme, which makes it better than poetry.</p>

<h2>The Macwood Caper</h2>

<p>Dirk Drake snubbed out his cigarette on the rain-slick bricks next to him and turned out of the alley, easing himself into the general flow of pedestrians practiced ease. There would be no way those goons could follow him now. He walked two blocks, then turned into a smoky, cheap bar on the corner. The other pedestrians were a little surprised, sure, but they lived in a detective-noir world. People spontaneously transformed into bars all the time here. Getting excited about something like that was a mug’s game. They kept walking, heads down in the rain.</p>

<p>Inside, Drake leaned on the bar and ignored the fact that if there was any continuity in this story from one paragraph to the next he’d be standing inside himself. He had some inner demons, sure, but he knew how to handle them.<br/>
“Next round’s on me, boys.” he said loudly, and everyone cheered, then came to the bar to place orders. In the din he was able to talk to the barkeeper quietly.<br/>
“Word on the street is, Mr. J ain’t to happy with you, Drake,” Pat the Barkeeper said. He really wished people would stop taking his name literally. His life was like an endless TSA screening process.</p>

<p>“I’m not here to make Mr. J happy. I got a job to do and I aim to do it.”</p>

<p>“What’d they offer you, that could make you switch sides like that?” Pat said.</p>

<p>“None of your business. Let’s just say they can make things easier on me. They got protection.”</p>

<p>“Come back, Dirk, and you won’t need protection. You know Mr. J can take care of you.”</p>

<p>Dirk didn’t say anything. He’d been offered quite a bit. Speed, Power, flexibility, and, of course, protection. He still wasn’t sure what he’d given up was worth it, though. He swallowed his drink in one gulp, made a face, then slapped a large wad of bills down on the counter.</p>

<p>“I’ll keep that in mind, Pat. Take care.”</p>

<p>Pat watched Dirk walk out of the bar, completely unconcerned that both the bar and everyone in it would cease to exist at the end of this paragraph. “If he hates the taste of Ginger Ale so much, why does he always order it?” Pat wondered aloud. But nobody answered. They all just stopped existing.</p>

<p>Dirk knew the way in. He slid silently down shadowed halls, drifted like a ghost through doors that should have set off more alarms than the announcement of an impending John Meyer concert–well, ghosts that weighed about 210 pounds and had a deep working knowledge of the type of security system used in this place– and at last was exactly where he wanted to be. Slowly he approached the dias in the middle of the room. Like most of the room itself, the dias was made of a single block of aluminum, elegantly carved and beautifully minimalist. And there, resting on a stand, which was resting on the dias, you see, I mean, not to detract from the action, but this should be made clear; on a stand on the dias was the object of his quest.</p>

<p>The Second Generation iPad Prototype.<a href="#footnote_1_1020" title="and you thought we’d never get around to the Apple-related stuff! Just wait until we work the holidays into this!">2</a></p>

<p>Dirk knew this was the most dangerous part of the mission. He knew this because he’s not stupid. The most dangerous part is always the part where you’re in the middle of the building of the company you’re trying to rob. Knowing this, he spent fully two minutes straining his senses to catch every sound, every flicker of light, every possible indication of a trap. But he’d made it. The alarms were turned off, completely unaware that he was there, and he was free. He reached out, and just as his hand was closing around the edge of the iPad a great, tolling startup chime rolled through the room. One seemingly solid aluminum wall lit up, bathing the room in light, and in the wall next to it a face appeared on a screen that Dirk knew wasn’t there a moment ago.</p>

<p>“Well well, Mr. Drake. I wish I could say I was surprised. We always knew you would return. What a pity that it has to be in such…confrontational circumstances.”</p>

<p>“I didn’t choose to leave, and I’m not too thrilled about being back.”</p>

<p>“But the money was too good, huh?”</p>

<p>“Let’s just say that I could win those seven flaming dares and still make less than they offered me to pull this heist.”</p>

<p>The man in the screen laughed. “Very clever. And now I’m to guess who is paying you, is that right? ‘Win those seven’ you said, which sounds suspiciously like “Windows 7″, so perhaps it’s Mr. B himself. “Flaming dares” or Daring Fireballs? and the heist? Well, we both know that was just a red herring. a John “Red” Herring. Well, I don’t think I’ll play, Mr. Drake.”</p>

<p>Dirk looked at the screen, hope and fear fighting in his heart.</p>

<p>“So what now? You got me. What’s your move?”</p>

<p>“My move, Mr. Drake? Just this. You’ve seen it. You know what we’re planning, at least on the surface. Unfortunately, that’s all you’re going to get. You’re free to get what you can for that information on the outside. Nothing you say is going to hurt us, indeed, any publicity is good publicity. You didn’t get what you were sent for, but you may be able to get something out of this after all. Merry Christmas, Mr. Drake.” <a href="#footnote_2_1020" title="Turns out that’s all the holiday cheer this story’s getting. Also, yes, we are well aware that Mr. J is Buddhist. But he’s also a retailer in America, and Christmas means something to anyone who sells things around here.">3</a></p>

<p>Two large, well-muscled and inexplicably aluminum-colored men walked to the center of the room and guided Dirk out of the building. Once they were off the property they turned around and left him, having never spoken a word. Drake walked off into the night. He wished it was more like Chicago, but this was suddenly Cupertino. It was fairly warm, even with the rain. He turned up his collar anyway, just for the look of the thing.</p>

<p>He had more information than a lot of people, and he might be able to get something out of it. But who to sell to? Giz? DF? Pogue? Mentally he checked down the list. Finally he decided on a buyer. He knew someone who would want the information, and was in a position to pay for it.</p>

<p>Far away, a phone rang.</p>

<p>“Dickson residence. Who’s calling?”</p>

<p>“Listen, Dickson. I’ve got a scoop. What’s it worth to ya?”</p>

<ol>
<li>Being me I would try to work a “fired. Out of a cannon” joke in here, but it really doesn’t scan at all. [<a href="#identifier_0_1020">↩</a>]</li>
<li>and you thought we’d never get around to the Apple-related stuff! Just wait until we work the holidays into this! [<a href="#identifier_1_1020">↩</a>]</li>
<li>Turns out that’s all the holiday cheer this story’s getting. Also, yes, we are well aware that Mr. J is Buddhist. But he’s also a retailer in America, and Christmas means something to anyone who sells things around here. [<a href="#identifier_2_1020">↩</a>]</li>
</ol>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Apple Drops Java: Some Thoughts]]></title>
    <link href="http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/10/apple-drops-java-some-thoughts/"/>
    <updated>2010-10-28T00:00:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://PogiNate.github.com/CANS/2010/10/apple-drops-java-some-thoughts</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<h1></h1>

<p>We here at CANS have been thinking long and hard about the whole Apple-Java thing. And, if you ask us, it’s kinda silly that we’re talking about ourselves in the plural. But we have no intention of stopping now. If we have learned anything from our time blogging we’ve learned that there’s no bad idea that can’t be made worse by sticking to it long after it stopped being useful or funny. This was hard-won knowledge, and we choose to ignore it, as is our constitutional right.</p>

<p>And speaking of rights, it isn’t wrong or right of Apple to stop writing their own</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
